hello and welcome to the 30th tutorial
on how to program g-script 2.
so in this tutorial i want to show you
how to make
ghani's or if you print out some candies
and first thing i want to do is open rc
go to
rc options
i think no we go to folder options
then we go to the bottom
and we need to put this line
right here
file
ghani's
slash star dot gani i already have it
here but you probably won't have it
unless you know your server already has
it
but if you got your server you probably
wouldn't so once we have that here we're
going to click apply
then what we're going to do is we're
going to open the out game rc
so i'm going to do that right now
in a second
then
we want to click
what we want to do
is click player
is this button here for the players
gonna go here click
edit rights
then once you do that
this should open up and you click this
tab here it says folder rights
then what you want to do
is you want to go here and put
where is it
read
level slash ganis
and then slash
star
this means that you can
edit the folder of levels
ganis and then whatever files in that
folder
read means that you can view them and
write means that you can save them there
so we're going to have this line of code
somewhere here we're going to click
apply
and close the rc
now in the in-game rc
if we click this button here for the
folders and things and we'll click this
plus sign we could see a new folder here
ganes
and with all the guns we have on the
server and i'm going to show you how to
make one
so the first thing we're going to do
is
close all this
go out of here
uh
and for the server name i'm going to
type login
okay now that we're here we're going to
play press start
click install packages
then click
developer tools i already have it
installed
but you will want to install this if you
want to make ghani's so you install it
you close this i'm going to enter my
server again
and what you want to do
is
open up your grawl folder now
so it should be in your c drive users
your name and then grow
at least that's what should be if you
install it in the default directory so
now we're going to do is since we
installed grawl
shop and all those other developer tools
we should find graw shop right here
and we're going to click it
to run it so this is girl shop
and with it you can create guns and edit
them
first what we're going to do
is make an image that we can add into
here
so to do that
what we want to do is
create an image first so let's open
our girl folder again
go to the bottom or something and right
click
click or click here right click new
then we're gonna click bitmap image
kinda hard to see one second
you can hear
new oh you can't see it there there
new bitmap image
i'm gonna click that and we should see
this here we're gonna name it or we're
not gonna name it yet we're gonna open
it now
click open paint
and we're going to edit it
so let's just make something really fast
let's call it
apple
there we have an apple now what we're
going to do is go to save as
and we're not going to put
we're not just going to save it like
this what we want to do
is first we're going to put the name
let's just name dm apple
and then here save as type we want to
save it as
i'll make it higher again
save it as a gif image what this is
going to do is automatically convert the
image to a 16
bit type image and we want that because
you can't add any other
bits or whatever anything higher than 16
into the
graph shop
so
we're going to click this save
says color quality might be reduced we
don't want that but we have to click ok
you can edit the edit a bit to make it
look nicer later on
so now
i should have two of them here
apple.js and the old one that doesn't
have anything to do with the old one
so now that we have this here we want to
upload it to the server
well not yet but we will
so here in girlshop what we're going to
do
is click this button right here
once we click that
this is going to pop up
asking us for the name of the image
we're going to put gm
dot
museumapple.gif
here's description doesn't really matter
what you put we'll just put apple
here you want to make sure you're not
putting an index number that already has
an image to it
if you go here and highlight over these
you'll see their index number this is 0
this is 10 11 12 13 this is 40. as you
can see there's no 20 it goes from 13 to
40 so we can put 20.
any other images we want to add we
should put 21 22 and
make sure we don't override any other
images then we're going to put the width
and the height of the image
and the starting point and the y point
now what this means is if we go to open
the image
open
with paint
the x and the y here
x and y
is where it's going to start so if we
put 0 it's going to start at the very
top left corner if we put maybe 10 10
it's going to start right here
then
this is the width and the height so it's
going to go start at 10
go 32 this way 30 to down it's going to
cut out that
piece and put it there but we want to
put the entire image so we're going to
put 0
and it doesn't really matter what else
we put because just something higher
than
18.
i'm just going to put 18
and 18.
now this part doesn't really matter you
can play with it play around with it if
you want but i'm not going to we're
going to add it now
and you can see our apple here
got added we can add transparency to it
later but right now let's
zoom in here
and add the apple down
so what we're going to do
is you can oh you can also change the
direction here
if you put
up you're going to have to add the apple
to all the different directions but
we're just going to use the down if
you're going to have a gun that has all
four directions yeah you have to go
through each and every direction make it
which is really boring but you know
whatever
so
now we have this here we're going to
delete shield
click the body and look for a new body
that looks better for what we're going
to use
here's a good one
next we're going to click it
press minus minus minus until it's under
the head but over the shadow
next what we're going to do is
find the arm
here's an arm
i'm going to take this
put it right there
take this apple and have it so you're
holding the apple
next we're going to take this
segment
copy it
and paste it
so we have this new segment
in this segment we're going to make it a
bit higher
click it copy paste
and here we're going to put
a bit higher again a bit higher again
copy paste
and a bit higher again and one more time
so now we have this
we can try to run it
that looks pretty good
you're lifting up the apple you can also
go into them
click them and change the length of them
so they last longer so we put 0.5
instead of 0.05 you can see it increases
it
and
doesn't look that good so we're just
going to put back the .05
if you want to you can also go to loop
so that the ghani loops back and forth
which is pretty good
we don't want that
so yeah
let's add one more
segment and make it one more time higher
and make it so it doesn't loop i don't
want it to loop
okay there
now we have it we're going to put
save as we don't want to save because
it's going to go over our id gani we
don't want that save as
and save it in any folder we want i want
to save it into where i put my own ganis
and i'm going to put
apple
hold dot
gani you have to put dot ghani or
because it doesn't automatically save it
as dakani which is weird but anyway we
save it
we can just put that over here then
let's open rc again
we have levels here
i'm going to press plus
go to ghani's
right click anywhere
upload
let's go find the image
there apple hold we also want to upload
the apple image don't forget that so
let's go to the images
and upload the apple image separately
let's go to images
oh wait that's not where i had it i had
it over here we can upload that
and it's there
now to test it out let's open some
weapon that we have attached to us like
zm test
and we're going to comment all this out
so it doesn't affect
us
then right over here we're going to put
function
on
weapon fired
so we select and press d and we're going
to put set any
apple hold
comma
no
let's try that out and see if it works
so i select zm test and press d and
there's argani
you can press d again and try it out you
can put it anywhere else you want
it it's your gandhi to keep
we may want to change the image so as
transparency but that's another day
anyway that concludes this tutorial and
i hope you understand how to add ghani's
and use them
and i'll see you next time